<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on GEOS</title>
    <link>https://libgeos.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on GEOS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://libgeos.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.11.2</title>
      <link>https://libgeos.org/posts/2023-03-16-geos-3-11-2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libgeos.org/posts/2023-03-16-geos-3-11-2-released/</guid>
      <description>As part of a batch release of patches for stable branches, the 3.11.2 release of GEOS is now available to download.
Release notes for the various branches are available: 3.10.5, and 3.11.2
The 3.11.2 release is a bug fix release.
 GEOSIntersection: Fix FE_INVALID exception on intersection of disjoint geometries (GH-791, Joris Van den Bossche &amp;amp; Dan Baston) Fix incorrect result from Envelope::disjoint (GH-791, Dan Baston) Fix handling of odd cases in PolygonHoleJoiner (JTS-946, Paul Ramsey, Martin Davis) Support gcc-13 (GH-743, Sergei Trofimovich) Disallow Inf envelopes in Quadtree, avoid inf loop (Paul Ramsey) GEOSUnaryUnion: Fix crash on collection containing empty point (GH-830, Dan Baston) GEOSSTRtree_iterate: Do not return removed items (GH-833, Dan Baston) IndexedFacetDistance: Fix crash with Inf coordinates (GH-821, Dan Baston) HausdorffDistance: Fix crash on collection containing empty point (GH-840, Dan Baston) MaximumInscribedCircle: Fix infinite loop with non-finite coordinates (GH-843, Dan Baston) DistanceOp: Fix crash on collection containing empty point (GH-842, Dan Baston) Guard against non-finite distances in Buffer/OffsetCurve (GH-661, Paul Ramsey)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.11.1</title>
      <link>https://libgeos.org/posts/2022-11-14-geos-3-11-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libgeos.org/posts/2022-11-14-geos-3-11-1-released/</guid>
      <description>As part of a batch release of patches for stable branches, the 3.11.1 release of GEOS is now available to download.
Release notes for the various branches are available: 3.9.4, 3.10.4, and 3.11.1
The 3.11.1 release is a bug fix release.
 Remove spurious version from &amp;ndash;libs geos-config options Fix PreparedGeometry to avoid crashes with EMPTY elements in input (GH-678, Martin Davis) Fix LineSegment.orientationIndex(LineSegment) (GH-699, Martin Davis) Fix DepthSegment comparison operation (GH-707, Martin Davis) Add OverlayNG support for simple GeometryCollection inputs (GH-716, Martin Davis) Fix TopologyPreservingSimplifier to produce stable results for Multi inputs (GH-718) Fix WKB hex endian test (GH-720, Paul Ramsey) Improve ConvexHull radial sort robustness (GH-724, Martin Davis) Use more robust Delaunay Triangulation frame size heuristic (GH-728, Martin Davis) Fix crash in GEOSIntersects with empty point inputs (GH-673, Dan Baston) Fix RelateOp for empty geometry and closed linear geometry (TRAC-1096, Dan Baston) Return 2D result on 2D input to GeometryPrecisionReducer (TRAC-1137, Dan Baston)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.11.0</title>
      <link>https://libgeos.org/posts/2022-07-01-geos-3-11-0-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libgeos.org/posts/2022-07-01-geos-3-11-0-released/</guid>
      <description>The 3.11.0 release of GEOS is now available to download.
This release includes new features for building &amp;ldquo;concave hulls&amp;rdquo; for both point and polygon input. For polygon input, the hull will be guaranteed to not cross into the interiors of the input polygons.
The line merger has been enhanced to support a mode that only merges lines which share orientation.
The offset curve algorithm has been updated to be more reliable for different kinds of semi-degenerate inputs, and may output different curves than the previous implementation, for those kinds of inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.10.3</title>
      <link>https://libgeos.org/posts/2022-06-03-geos-3-10-3-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libgeos.org/posts/2022-06-03-geos-3-10-3-released/</guid>
      <description>As part of a batch release of patches for all stable branches, the 3.10.3 release of GEOS is now available to download.
Release notes for the various branches are available: 3.7.4, 3.8.3, 3.9.3 and 3.10.3.
The 3.10.3 release is a bug fix release.
 VoronoiDiagramBuilder::setSites(const CoordinateSequence&amp;amp;) return sorted (GH-551) Add SnappingNoder seeding (Martin Davis) Fix RelateOp (and intersects predicate) for lines with intersections very near boundary (GH-570, Martin Davis) Fix segfault in Hausdorff distance with empty geometries (GH-569) Fix inf loop in PolygonTriangulator (GH-574, Andrew Stelter) Fix short circuit from TemplateSTRtree query (GH-577, Andrew Stelter) Fix IsValidOp to handle repeated node points (JTS-845, Martin Davis) Fix IsSimpleOp to handle closed LineStrings with repeated endpoints (JTS-851, Martin Davis) Add OverlayNG area check heuristic (JTS-812, Paul Ramsey) Improve test_geos_unit application error checking and reporting (Martin Davis) Fix LengthIndexedLine (via LengthLocationMap fix) (JTS-859, Martin Davis) Fix PolygonHoleJoiner (JTS-862, Martin Davis) Fix crash in GeometryNoder on empty intpu (GH-601, Paul Ramsey) Handle case where user sets explicit absolute lib and include dirs (GH-608, Paul Ramsey) Fix MinimumDiameter getMinimumRectangle for flat input (JTS-875, Martin Davis) Fix HilbertEncoder difference in ARM vs x64 (GH-579, Paul Ramsey) Fix BufferOp inverted ring check (JTS-878, Martin Davis)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.10.2</title>
      <link>https://libgeos.org/posts/2021-11-02-geos-3-10-2-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libgeos.org/posts/2021-11-02-geos-3-10-2-released/</guid>
      <description>The 3.10.2 release of GEOS is now available to download.
This release is a bug fix release.
 Fix crash in MonotoneChain with empty CoordinateSequence (GH-539, Sandro Santilli) Fix crash in GeoJSONWriter in case of empty points (TRAC-1139, Paul Ramsey) Improve BuildArea performance (TRAC-1122, Sandro Santilli) Fix unaryUnion to avoid segfault with empty polygon (GH-501, Mike Taves) Fix memory leak on exception in prepared geometry (GH-506, Dan Baston) Iterator invalidation in rare cases (GH-508, Momtchil Momtchev) Infinite loop on collapsed input to MaximumInscribedCircle (Paul Ramsey) Write LinearRing to GeoJSON as LineString (TRAC-1140, Paul Ramsey) Fix PolygonEarClipper to handle collapsed corners (GH-526, Martin Davis) Fix GEOSSTRtree_remove for empty tree (GH-544, Dan Baston) Fix crash on query of STRtree with removed items (GH-545, Dan Baston)q  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.10.1</title>
      <link>https://libgeos.org/posts/2021-11-02-geos-3-10-1-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libgeos.org/posts/2021-11-02-geos-3-10-1-released/</guid>
      <description>The 3.10.1 release of GEOS is now available to download.
  This release is primarily to fix some version numbering issues in the initial 3.10.0 source tarball. Some extra fixes are bundled as well.
 Fixes a mistake in constants used to select WKB flavor in C API Fixes a crash when reducing precision on a LinearRing Fixes GeoJSON crash on invalid input Uses std::sqrt exclusively, to support the Solaris build Fixes mistaken version numbers in some parts of 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version 3.10.0</title>
      <link>https://libgeos.org/posts/2021-10-01-geos-3-10-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://libgeos.org/posts/2021-10-01-geos-3-10-released/</guid>
      <description>The 3.10 release of GEOS is now available to download.
  This release includes the following new features in the C API (and of course underlying changes to the C++ code to support these features):
 CAPI additions for testing whether geometries are within a distance of each other, GEOSDistanceWithin and GEOSPreparedDistanceWithin CAPI addition for adding extra vertices to a geometry, GEOSDensify CAPI additions for high-performance construction/reading of coordinate sequences from/to memory buffers, GEOSCoordSeq_copyFromArrays, GEOSCoordSeq_copyFromBuffer, GEOSCoordSeq_copyToArrays, and GEOSCoordSeq_copyToBuffer CAPI addition for new validity enforement algorithm, GEOSMakeValidWithParams CAPI addition for ISO WKB output, GEOSWKBWriter_getFlavor and GEOSWKBWriter_setFlavor CAPI addition to create a constrained delaunay of polygonal input, GEOSConstrainedDelaunayTriangulation    There is a new utility for running arbitrary GEOS commands against input files, geosop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
